Senior,
学长
you didn't know that
您是不知道
my boyfriend
我男朋友啊
used to bring me here
他经常带我来
to shop in this street.
这条街逛街
This hot pot restaurant,
这家火锅店
we used to come here, too.
我们也经常来吃
Every time, we sat
我们每次都坐在
there.
那个位置
White clothes,
白衣服
long hair,
长头发
a girl.
女的
Your boyfriend?
你男朋友啊
Look at you.
你看看你
You can't even eat an ice cream
吃个冰激凌都
with me.
唧唧歪歪的
Look at him.
你看看人家
Hold it carefully.
你好好拎着啊
If the cake is broken,
蛋糕要破相了
you will be beaten.
你也得破相
How's it going?
怎么样
It's okay. Everything's fine.
还行吧 一切顺利
Where did you get all these stuff?
你这些东西从哪儿来的
I had a lot of balloons
上次给刘彦泽告白
left from my last confession to Liu Yanze.
剩了挺多气球的
Throw them away now!
快扔了吧
How inauspicious!
多不吉利呀
Shut up!
闭嘴
Dango, how did you know
团子 你怎么知道
they finished early today?
他们今天结束得早啊
I played a little trick.
姐们我略施小计
Silly
那傻不啦叽的
Qiu Lingyan and Ding Li
秋凌烟跟丁力
are in the Actuarial Science Club.
俩人是精算社的
The president is my buddy
社长是我哥们
who gave them both some work.
给他们俩安排点活
Nice!
可以呀
But...
但
But we don't have the key.
但是咱们没钥匙啊
What should we do?
怎么办
Didn't I say I would nail it?
我不是说我会搞定的吗
Great!
行啊
Although you are just a trainee teacher,
就算是实习的
you are
四舍五入
still a teacher.
也算是个老师啊
Why are you doing
怎么净干些
such thieving things?
偷鸡摸狗的事呢
What thieving things?
什么偷鸡摸狗
Do I have this skill?
我有那手艺吗
This key was made by the coach of team one,
这钥匙是人家一队教练
Meng.
老孟给配的
Why did he give you the key?
他给你钥匙干嘛啊
But
不是
isn't team one
他们一队
trying to win us?
不是要整咱们吗
We coaches
我们这些教练呐
are superstructure.
那都是上层建筑
You think we are like you
你以为跟你们这些
little kids
小屁孩一样呢
who quarrel every day.
每天喊打喊杀的
Little kids.
小屁孩
-Go. Let's start!  -Start!
走 开始 开始吧
Nan Bei, you take these things.
南北 你来拿东西
Cake, cake.
蛋糕 蛋糕
You all let me take them by myself!
你们都让我一个人拿啊
Well,
那个
I saw you in the mirror
我在火锅店的
at the hot pot restaurant.
镜子里看见你了
Then explain.
那你解释吧
For what?
解释什么呀
She is
她就是我们
one of the new workers in our department
部门新来的一个干事
who are grateful for my
说是挺感谢我
help in her daily work.
平时对她的帮助吧
Then
然后
she invited me to dinner.
就请我吃了顿饭
Are you angry?
生气了
What's wrong about that?
哎呀 这有什么的呀
I have things to do.
我还有事要忙
I'll go first.
我先走了
Is this a big deal?
这是什么大事吗
Just a dinner.
就是吃个饭
There's really nothing else.
真没别的事了
I haven't asked you yet.
我还没问你呢
Who's that guy next to you?
你旁边那男的谁呀
A teammate in Debate Club.
辩论社的队友
That's it.
这不就得了
Well
哦
You can go shopping with your teammate,
你跟队友逛个街就行
but I can't have a dinner with my colleague.
我跟同事吃个饭就不行
Besides that,
再说了
our problem
咱们俩的问题
is not only my fault.
不是我一个人的事吧
Are you having an affair with her?
你们之间暧不暧昧
You know it best.
你自己心里清楚
How does it become my problem?
怎么还变成我的问题了
Doesn't it?
不是吗
Tao Hao
陶好
What you do every day is facing the phone
你每天就对着那个手机
and sending messages all the time.
没完没了地发消息
I was thinking
我就在想
how can a student
我说一个学生
be so busy?
能有多忙啊
You always
你每天总是
try to please everyone around you.
想讨好身边所有人
Then I'll ask you, Tao Hao,
那我问你 陶好
what about me?
我呢
That's the right name for you.
你这名字真没取错
Do you remember
你记不记得
I am your boyfriend?
我是你男朋友啊
On your list every day,
我每天在你的列表里
don't I have
就没有
a priority?
那么一点优先权吗
Between how you deal with me now
你现在应付我
and how you deal with those people in your department,
和应付你们部门那帮人
is there any difference?
有什么区别呀
When the problem between us
我们俩之间的问题
started?
什么时候开始
Don't you know that?
你心里没点数吗
Do you know
你知道我跟你谈恋爱
how tiring and boring it is for me to be your boyfriend?
有多累 有多无聊吗
Anyway, I came to you today
反正我今天是主动过来
to explain this thing to you.
找你解释这个事的
I think my sincerity
我觉得我的诚意
is enough.
已经很足了
If you are still misunderstanding me,
你要是还在误会我
I really have nothing to say.
我真就没话可说了
I'll go.
我走了
Sister Tao Hao
陶好姐
Wish you to be more and more attractive!
祝你越来越漂亮
Hope Hao
祝小好姐
to lead us to an early victory
早日带我们取得胜利
and get the champion!
拿到冠军
Good luck with Hao's
祝小好同学
relationship and education!
感情学业双丰收
Wish dear Hao
祝亲爱的小好姐
in the new year
在新的一年里面
to be happy
每天都开开心心
and joyful every day!
快快乐乐
But today is not my birthday!
但今天不是我生日啊
We know.
我们知道
Tomorrow is your birthday.
明天才是你生日嘛
But tomorrow we
可是明天不是
need to give your time
要把你的时间
to you and your boyfriend.
让给你和你男朋友嘛
That's why today we
所以我们今天
are celebrating your birthday.
就替你提前过了
What's wrong with you, Hao?
小好姐 你怎么了
You called me in such a hurry.
这么急叫我
What's the matter?
什么事
Break up!
分手
As to this kind of scum,
这种渣男
why not break up, or stay him for the New Year?
不分手留着过年吗
Am I right, Xiaoyu?
是不是 小鱼
Exactly.
就是
Having ruffled her hair!
撩头发了
Doesn't ruffling hair mean an affair?
撩头发还不是暧昧呀
What the hell?
什么东西呀
What is the relationship between them?
什么关系他们是
I have such a good relation with Nan Bei,
我跟南北关系这么好
but when did you
你什么时候
see he ruffle my hair?
看他撩我头发了
Right, you just pulled my hair.
是 光薅我头发了
We're not the same.
咱俩不一样
Hao
小好姐
Don't jump to conclusion.
不用那么着急下定论
What if that woman
撩头发万一那女的
has Parkinson's?
帕金森呢
Right, I think
是 我觉得
he has taken the initiative to tell you
他都主动跟你说了
instead of hiding,
没有隐瞒
maybe
说不定
there is really nothing wrong with them.
就真没有什么事呢
Just ruffling her hair?
不就撩下头发吗
What do you mean just ruffling her hair?
什么叫就撩下头发
You talk like you are scum.
你这么说话你就是渣男
I am scum.
我是渣男
This really can not continue.
这样下去真的不行
See?
看到没有
Look at Ma Nan.
人家马楠
Although he is careless and casual at ordinary times,
平时虽然说吊儿郎当的
on this kind of
但是在这种
principle issues,
原则性问题上
he is still very reliable.
还是很靠得住的
This cake really can't
这蛋糕这样下去
go on like this,
真的不行
it will be sour.
会酸的
I'm so sorry.
不好意思
Everyone is
大家这么
so happy for my birthday,
开开心心给我过生日
but I'm ruining it.
我扫大家兴了
I'll cut the cake for all of you.
我给大家切蛋糕
So nice!
好漂亮
It's a fruit cake.
还是水果的
Do you like it?
喜欢吗
It was made by me and Nan Bei.
我跟南北亲手做的哟
Hao
小好姐
It's okay to eat the cake later.
蛋糕晚点吃没有关系的
But you need to know
但是你要知道
you're the only one we're supporting.
我们支持的只有你
Right.
对
We are your
我们才是你
strongest backing.
最坚强的后盾
Ok!
嗯
Then I'll go back to my dorm later
那我一会儿回寝室
and send him a message
给他发个信息
to apologize.
道个歉
Hao
小好姐
Well, we're not so
这我们就不是很
supportive of you.
支持你了
I thought about it on the way over here
我来的路上想过了
and I thought I had put
我应该给了他
a lot of pressure on him.
挺大压力的
Being in a relationship with
跟我这种性格
someone like me
的人在一起
must be exhausting.
应该真的很累吧
Hao
小好姐
You can't think of yourself that way.
你不能这么想自己
You don't have to think about him right now
你现在不用考虑他
and don't think
也不用考虑
what advice we are giving.
我们到底给了什么建议
All you need to think about right now
你现在最需要考虑的
is what you really want
是你自己到底想要什么
I just want to
我就是想
make everyone around me happy.
让身边的人都开心
That's the problem.
这就是问题
So what are we going to do now?
那我们现在该怎么办呀
How about
要不
going out?
出去逛逛
Xiaoyu
小鱼
Where's Hao?
小好姐呢
Hao went back to her dorm
小好姐回寝室了
and said she wanted to be alone.
说一个人静一静
I really can't stand Hao
我是真的忍不了小好姐
being bullied like that.
被这么欺负
That's a family matter.
那是人家的家事
How do we solve it?
咱们怎么管呀
Go have a showdown with that guy.
去找那男的摊牌
If he is truly a good man,
他要真是个好样的
we can keep him for now and see what happens.
那就先留着他以观后效
If he is really a scum,
他要真是个渣男
let him disappear.
让他消失
Exactly!
没错
Well...
那个
Are you a bit
你们这样是不是有点
out of bounds?
越界了
Hey
哎
At the moment of your confession to Liu Yanze,
你跟刘彦泽告白那会儿
did you think I was meddling?
你嫌我多管闲事吗
Not at all.
没有啊
I was hoping you'd help me more.
我还希望你带着我呢
See?
你看吧
Good friends
好朋友之间
need to cross the line.
就是要越界的
Right.
就是
What do you think?
你说说
I think Xiaoyu is right.
我觉得小鱼说得对
What?
啊
Tao Hao's problem
陶好的问题
is extremely serious.
已经病入膏肓了
As her friends,
我们作为她的
we surly need to help her.
朋友当然要帮
But the problem is with her.
可是问题出在她身上
We only need to
我们只要
treat her.
治疗她就可以了
The problem is that we failed.
问题是咱们失败了呀
Counting on you guys
我说指望你们
is not as reliable as counting on me.
还不如指望我自己呢
I'm thirsty. I want to drink milk tea.
我渴了 我想喝奶茶
Will you say?
你说不说
Tell her.
别跟她压着
Tao Hao's problem
陶好的问题呢
has two aspects.
分两个层面
The first aspect
第一个层面
is
就表现于
her pleasing personality.
她的讨好型人格
She always
她一定要
meets the needs of everyone around her.
满足周围所有人的要求
She doesn't say no to people.
她不会拒绝别人
And this kind of mindset
而这种心态呢
will become
就会演变成
the appearance of pleasing others,
讨好别人的表象
which means she must meet
一定要满足
everyone's requirements.
所有人的要求
But in this way
可是这样呢
she will be very tired.
往往会变得非常累
The second aspect
第二个层面呢
is that she goes against human nature.
就是她违背了人的本性
What do you mean?
什么意思
Man is an animal that seeks profit and avoids harm.
人是趋利避害的动物
But now, she
可是她现在
puts the needs of others
把别人的需求
above her own ones.
放在自己的需求之上
Why?
这是为什么呢
You are all students in the national key university.
一个个还九八五学生呢
You don't even know this.
这都不知道
Moreover, you are a teacher.
还有老师
Because in her mind,
因为在她的概念里面
pleasing others
讨好别人
means acquiring
就是获得
recognition from others.
别人对她的认可
The recognition of others
那别人认可了她
will lead to a
就会产生一个
very good social relationship.
非常良好的社交关系
Once she doesn’t satisfy others,
那一旦满足不了别人
this social relationship
这段社交关系
will be very dangerous.
就会变得非常危险
She will be nervous
她就会惴惴不安
until she pleases others,
直到她讨好了别人
or thinks
或者她自认为
she pleases others.
讨好了别人
But this
可是这样
is often a thankless effort.
往往是吃力不讨好
Why don't you
你说你怎么
want to graduate?
就是不想毕业呢
With your eloquence,
就你这种口才
even you don't want to be a psychologist,
不当心理医生
you can still be a master
在大街上装个大师
to swindle money.
招摇撞骗也行啊
Don't interrupt!
你能不能别打岔
To conclude,
总结一下陈词
fundamentally
从根本上讲
she is socially insecure.
她缺乏社交安全感
Her sister
她的妹妹
and experience without friends
她中学时期
in middle school period
没有朋友的经历
both can cause a sense of insecurity.
都会造成缺乏安全感
That's why she tries to
所以她才会用这种方式
maintain social relationships in this way,
去维护社交关系
and she's afraid to say no.
不敢拒绝别人
So what can we do?
那要怎么办
Easy.
简单
If she has a disease, treat it.
有病治病
Senior,
学长
you usually look like a misanthrope.
你平时一副厌世的样子
When it comes to Tao Hao,
怎么一到陶好姐的事
why are you so positive?
你就这么积极啦
Recently, I've been studying
我最近在研究
how people go from mental illness
人是怎么从心理疾病
to psychopathy.
演变成心理变态的
She is my observation target.
她是我的观察目标
Then master,
那大师
how to treat the disease?
这病怎么治啊
Easy.
简单
Just give her a sense of security.
给她安全感就好了
Then how to give her that?
那怎 怎么给呢
What did you say?
什么怎么给她安全感
We are her sense of security.
咱们就是她的安全感
Actually I think
其实我觉得
Tao Hao already knows.
陶好已经知道了
She just doesn't realize yet that
只不过她还没有意识到
she has had
自己已经得到了
this sense of security.
这种安全感
When she does,
得等她明白以后
the next thing she needs to do is
接下来要做的就是
change the pleasing personality
改变她长期以来形成的
she's been developing for so long.
讨好型性格
So how to take action?
那具体怎么行动起来呢
Just like before.
就跟以前一样
Let her say no.
让她说不
But we have failed.
可咱们都失败了
That's because
那是因为
I didn't take action.
我没出马
In fact,
其实吧
he has good intentions.
他出发点是好的
But when he does something like this,
但是他来这么一出
it always makes me feel a little...
总让我感觉有点
Showing off.
太嘚瑟
Pretty good.
挺好的
It's cool.
多帅啊
A man has to be a man.
男人就得有担当啊
What do you think?
怎么样
Declare your opinions.
表个态吧
Agree or disagree?
到底同不同意
Are we pushing her too hard?
是不是有点逼太紧了
I think it's reasonable.
我觉得挺合理的
Right. Hao.
就是 小好
Have a try.
你试试吧
Listen,
你看是这样啊
you can do the work of the student union,
学生会分内的事可以做
but don't do anything unrelated to it.
分外的事一件都不要做
After 9 p.m.,
晚上九点以后
don't answer the phone.
电话不要接
It can't be called reporting work.
那么晚不叫汇报工作
It is harassing.
叫骚扰
It's ok to help the teacher,
帮老师打下手可以
but let them buy their own coffee.
但咖啡让他们自己去买
At this age,
这么大年龄
if they don't move,
再不活动活动
their joints will rust.
关节就生锈了
It is same to
还有学生会的干事
the members of the student union.
也是一样
You can teach them but can't do for them.
可以教 但不能代劳
You'll have the baby
娃你自己以后生
yourself.
会有的
You don't have to take care of other babies.
用不着帮别人管
Agree or not?
同不同意
How about
要不
making a concrete analysis of a concrete problem?
具体问题具体分析
Well,
嗯
I think don't be so absolute.
我觉得别那么彻底
In case of a special emergency,
万一遇到特别紧急的事
I'll take care of it.
我还是去处理一下
Well,
嗯
I know.
我知道了
I don't agree
所有的事情
with anything.
我一概不同意
Well,
嗯
very good.
非常好
Go on.
继续
I know you all did it for me,
我知道你们是为了我好
fearing that I am tired.
怕我累
But I always felt like
但我总觉得
this proposal
这个提议
is not the solution.
也不是解决问题的方法
So you turned down
所以你是拒绝了
our proposal,
我们的提议
right?
对吧
Not really.
也不是
How about taking the long view?
要不从长计议
Nice.
很好
No. Ma Nan, what do you mean?
不是 马楠 你什么意思
Take your time.
不要急
You see.
你看
You are saying no
你这不就拒绝
to our proposal.
我们提议了吗
You
你这个病啊
have to recognize that
一定要认清楚
conflict is inevitable.
冲突是必然存在的
You can't always
你不可能时时刻刻都
control everything,
控制住全场
right?
对吧
Hao
小好姐
We thought
我们之前是觉得
you were just helpful,
你就是乐于助人
like an octopus, always giving others a hand.
八爪鱼属性
But now we know
可是现在我们知道了
you also get tired and break down.
你也会累 也会崩溃
We are a family.
我们是一家人
We're not giving up on you!
我们不会放弃你的
Right!
嗯
I know.
我知道了
Ok.
好
Now let's go to step two.
接下来我们第二步
Please.
请
OK.
嗯
Well
好
The next period,
接下来的一段时间
we mainly train
我们主要训练
thinking shielding.
思维屏蔽
In a nutshell,
简单地来讲
when you are unable
就是当你无法
to quickly understand
快速的理解
and refute the other party's points of view,
和反驳对方观点的时候
do not accept
要做到不接受
or think about the other party's points of view,
不思考对方的观点
so as not to be carried away,
以免被带跑偏
and blurt out disagreement.
同时脱口而出不同意
Do you agree?
你们同意吗
Disagree!
我不同意
Very good.
非常好
You see.
你看啊
This is a one-on-one training session
这既是辩论队的
for the debate team,
一对一对辩训练
and it's also carefully designed for you.
也是精心为你设计
Let's start to say no
咱们从小事开始
from the small things,
试着拒绝
just like in a debate.
就像在辩论场上一样
How about that?
怎么样
I...
我
I am the opposing side.
我是反方
My fellow debater,
对方辩友
I disagree.
我不同意
Inexplicably good.
莫名的好爽
Right.
嗯
Gosh...
哎
Hui, not done yet?
小慧 还没忙完啊
Yes.
嗯
This excel is too difficult.
这个电子表格太难了
I may not be in time.
我可能来不及了
Do you have something to do later?
你一会儿有事吗
I have a date with my boyfriend.
我约了男朋友
Maybe it's too late today.
可能今天真的来不及了
I will finish a midnight movie with him
我跟他看完午夜的电影
and back to the bedroom about two o 'clock.
回到寝室大概两点多钟
I don't need to sleep when I'm done this excel
做完正好不用睡
and take class in the tomorrow morning.
明天一早上早课去
How can you not sleep?
怎么可以不睡觉呢
But Mr. Li has said that
可是李主任说了
it has to be finished today.
今天一定得做完
You can send it to me.
那你发给我吧
I have nothing to do right now.
我正好现在没事做
Great!
好啊
Thank you, Hao.
谢谢小好姐
Once upon a time, there was a farmer.
从前有一个农民
Before the storm came,
在暴风雨来临之前
he did not build a warm shelter.
没有搭好暖棚
What to do?
怎么办呢
He asked Mr. Wang next door for help.
他就找隔壁老王帮忙
They signed an agreement.
还签了协议
If the crops went bad,
如果庄稼坏了
Mr. Wang was to blame.
还得算老王的
He
他自己呢
went back to have a baby with his wife.
就回去跟媳妇生娃了
As to this kind of crafty
你说这种奸诈狡猾
and disgusting behavior,
恶心至极的做法
Tao Hao,
陶好
if you were Mr. Wang, would you agree with that?
你要是老王你同意吗
I disagree.
我不同意
Hao,
那小好姐
I won't bother you.
我就不麻烦你了
I'll do it myself.
我自己回去做吧
Hui.
小慧
Hao, how's your body?
小好 身体怎么样了
Mr. Li, much better.
李主任 好多了
Ma Nan
马楠
Put this file in order.
你把这个文件整理一下
Later
晚点呢
Make the minutes of the meeting for me.
做个会议记录给我
You can ask Hao about the format.
格式就问下小好就行了
But, Mr. Li...
不是 老李
Mr. Li, I have things to do tonight!
老李 我晚上还有事呢
Mr. Li!
老李
Well
那个
Would you like to
要不然你受累
help me with that?
帮我做一下
I disagree.
我不同意
What are you doing here?
你怎么来了
Happy Birthday!
生日快乐
I booked
我晚上订了
your favorite Japanese restaurant tonight.
你最爱吃的那家日料店
After the dinner,
吃完我们
how about going to the movies?
去看电影怎么样
I'm a little busy today.
我今天比较忙
Maybe another time.
改天吧
You know
你也知道
it's hard to book at that Japanese restaurant.
那家日料店很难订的
Let's go.
走吧
Well, if you change your mind,
那你要是改主意了
then text me,
那就给我发消息
ok?
好吧
I wish you good fortune and longevity.
我祝你福寿与天齐
Happy birthday to you.
恭祝你生日快乐
Your son
我说你儿子长得
doesn't look like
本来就不合群
other ducks.
不像个鸭子
You still
你非得
put a red scarf on it.
给它再系个红围巾
Are you going to isolate it?
你是不是要孤立它
I disagree.
我不同意
This is what we call big frog in a small pond.
我们这叫鹤立鸭群
Not like your turtle,
哪儿像你那乌龟似的
crouching neck all the time,
整天缩着脖子
like it's hiding from others.
跟见不得人似的
I disagree.
我不同意
We call this low-key.
我们这叫低调
Don't like you playboys.
跟你们似的都大猪蹄子
I disagree.
我不同意
Hao's boyfriend
小好姐男朋友
is a playboy.
那叫大猪蹄子
I am a potential stock.
我们这叫潜力股好吧
I disagree.
我不同意
Hao's boyfriend
小好姐她男朋友
is a scum.
那叫渣男
I disagree.
我不同意
Hao's boyfriend
小好姐她男朋友
was wrong.
是做得不对
But he still can
但那也在
be forgiven.
原谅的范围内啊
Hao
小好姐
has been angry for several days.
已经赌了几天气了
Just ignore him for some days.
晾他几天就完了呗
I disagree.
我不同意
You have to be single-minded in a relationship.
谈恋爱就得专一
Going out for dinner with others
俩人单独出去
must let me know.
吃饭不报备都不行
I disagree.
我不同意
If we
假如咱俩
both have a boyfriend or girlfriend...
要有了男女朋友
Take Dango as an example.
你就说团子吧
If Dango has a boyfriend,
团子要有了男朋友的话
can't she have a dinner with me?
跟我吃顿饭还不行啊
It's just a relationship.
谈恋爱就是谈恋爱
I am not finding
那又不是找一个
a mother who's in charge of everything,
什么都管的妈
or a leader
也不是找一个
who needs to be reported with everything.
什么都得报备的领导
I say I disagree.
我说我不同意
I also disagree
我也不同意
my idea.
自己的想法
But I agree with yours.
但我同意你的
Do you agree with mine?
你同意我的吗
Hao is an almost perfect girl.
小好这姑娘哪儿都好
Her only shortcoming is too kind.
唯一的缺点就是太好
But you came up with a great idea.
不过你们这个点子挺妙
Thanks to Ma Nan this time.
这次也是多亏了马楠了
I just don't know if his folk remedy
就是不知道他这个偏方
will work.
到底管不管用
Ma Nan,
马楠
that little weasel,
那个小滑头
you need to keep an eye on him.
你们得盯紧点
The boy has too many wicked ideas.
小子鬼点子太多
I'm afraid that he will have some bad ideas one day.
不定哪天我怕他跑偏了
Sa
小撒
The future of this team depends on you.
团队的未来将来靠你了
I disagree.
我不同意
Sir, I, I'm sorry.
教练 对 对不起
I, I didn't mean that.
我 我不是那个意思
I just trained like this these days.
我 就训练这两
The situation in the debate
辩论场上的形势
change rapidly.
瞬息万变
You are all here.
大家都在
I just got the message.
我刚刚收到了消息
The next semi-final debate's
下一场半决赛的
topic is here.
辩题已经出来了
Setting a person image is advantageous
立人设是利大于弊
or disadvantageous?
还是弊大于利
So from now on,
所以从现在开始
We need to start
我们也要开始
getting ready for the game.
好好准备比赛了
I disagree.
我不同意
It can be agreed.
这个可以同意
Training time for the team one
一队的训练时间
is almost here.
马上就到了
Please team two
麻烦请二队的同学
and somebody
和某人
go out.
出去吧
Go out.
出去
I disagree.
我不同意
As to this classroom,
这间教室
we have half the use of it.
我们占一半的使用权
Although at ordinary times
虽然平时
We are more sensible
我们比较识大体
and put you first,
以你们为重
but in our time of need
但是在我们需要的时候
we also have
我们也有
the right to use this classroom.
这间教室的使用权
Do you agree?
你同意吗
I disagree.
不同意
As an auxiliary team,
你们作为辅助队
you should fully cooperate
应当全力配合
with we team one.
我们一队的安排
I disagree.
我不同意
We all joined the contest.
都是打比赛的
Training classroom should give priority to the contest.
训练教室比赛优先
Whoever has the schedule has the final say.
谁有日程谁说了算
Do you agree?
你同意吗
Disagree.
不同意
Routine training
日常训练
is as important as the contest preparation.
和赛前准备同样重要
I disagree.
我不同意
I...
我
Can't you just let us use it?
你就不能让我们一下吗
Let's go.
走吧
What?
不是
Really?
真的假的
Let them use this time.
就让他们一次
Dango, Dango.
团子 团子
What's the situation, Dango?
什么情况 团子
You are awesome!
你太牛了
Dango
团子
You are great!
你太棒了
What happened?
发生什么了
Mr. Li
李主任
The lesson plans you asked me to make
你让我弄的教案
has been sent over to you.
我刚刚发过去了
Please have a look.
您看一下
Mr. Zhang
张老师
An alternative to your course selection
你选课的备选方案
have been finished.
我都已经弄好了
I just e-mailed it to you.
刚刚发你邮箱了
Please remember to check it.
您记得查收一下
Hui
小慧
Your report
你的那个报告
has been done,
我都已经弄好
and I put it on your desk.
放你桌上了
Remember to pick it up tomorrow.
你明天记得过来拿
Well, I...
那个 我
I heard it all.
我都听到了
Let me explain.
你听我解释
There is a reason.
我是有原因的
Today is Hui's boyfriend's birthday
小慧她男朋友今天生日
which only happens once a year.
一年就这么一次
It's not good for her not to go.
她不去不太好
I really rejected as much as I could.
真的能推的我都推了
Then we all worked
那我们之前
in vain before.
不都白忙活了吗
I, I didn't
我 我不是
mean to do anything.
故意要去做什么的
I'm not tired.
我不累
I'm happy, too
我也挺开心的
I...
我
I'm so heartbroken.
我好心痛啊
You let me down.
你太让我失望了
I'm sorry to let you down.
是我不好让你们失望了
I can't control myself.
我控制不了我自己
Come here.
来啊
I know.
我知道
I understand you.
我理解你
Aren't you disappointed at me?
你不对我失望吗
No one can change
任何人都没有办法
in an instant.
一瞬间变样的
Just like a smoker
就像有烟瘾的人
can't quit smoking
不可能一下子
at once.
就把烟戒掉
Even if he quits,
就算戒掉了
he also needs a long process.
也需要一个漫长的过程
I'm sure you'll be fine.
我相信你会好的
Really?
真的吗
Really.
真的
I trust you.
我信任你
I hope you can also
我希望你也能
trust yourself.
信任你自己
At present,
你现在啊
what you need most
最需要做的
is to have a good rest.
就是好好地休息
Come.
来吧
First,
首先
close your eyes.
先闭上你的眼睛
Follow me.
跟我做
Inhale.
吸气
Yes.
对
Exhale.
呼气
Inhale.
吸
It will be just fine.
会好的
There should be applause.
此处应该有掌声
Nan Bei, are you going to
南北 你这是打算
show us a program of
给我们讲一档
Listening to Nan Bei's Story?
南北讲故事是吧
I don't want to criticize you,
不是我说你们啊
but you
你们啊
truly don't know how to think about yourselves.
太不懂得思考自己
Why did we
咱们之前
keep winning before?
为什么一直赢啊
The opponents we've met before
咱们之前遇到的对手
could be won with a little talk.
光是打嘴炮就能赢了
But the opponents we will meet this time
但这次咱们遇到的对手
are on a par with us.
和咱们旗鼓相当
What should we focus on?
拼的是什么
We should focus on the creativity.
拼的是创意
As far as this video is concerned,
就这个视频而言
is it particularly
是不是特别
appropriate for our next game?
符合咱们下场的比赛
Yes.
是
But it's a debate contest,
但是我们这个是辩论赛
not a short video contest.
又不是短视频大赛
In previous contests,
之前确实有比赛
there are indeed individual precedents using a short video.
用视频的个别先例
But Nan Bei,
但是南北
is your video a little
你这个视频会不会有点
like a stream of consciousness?
太意识流了
We also need time
而且还要花时间
to explain to the audience.
给观众解释
Indeed.
确实啊
B...But, Nan Bei,
但 但是 南北
First of all, your video
首先你这个视频拍得
is great.
很好啊
But short videos
但是短视频呢
are only auxiliary.
只能作为辅助作用
After all, you can't expect
你毕竟不能指望着
all audience
全场那么多观众
to fully
都百分之百地
understand
能够理解你这短片
the main idea of your video, right?
当中的中心思想 对吧
Right.
对
And it lacks artistry.
而且还缺乏艺术性
Do you know what artistry is?
你懂什么是艺术性吗
Do you know?
你懂吗
I think that's a good idea.
我觉得这个思路可以
It's a very good concept.
概念特别好
Recently, the film and television department of our school
最近我们学校影视系
is selecting scripts.
在评选剧本
You, me and Dandan,
你我 加上蛋蛋
we three
咱们三个
refine the story
把这个故事完善一下
and then we can get a production fee.
就能争取一笔制作费
And then maybe
然后说不定
the New Scriptwriters Award is ours.
新锐编剧奖也是我们的
That's why
要不然就说
you're the best debater.
你是最佳辩手呢
However,
不过啊
this kind of visual labeling presentation
这种直观的标签化呈现
is really able to
确实是能够
deepen the view.
加深持方观点
But
但是呢
should we
我们是不是
consider
应该考虑一下
how can we make
怎么样才能让
it fit the contest occasion?
它契合比赛的场合
What do you think, Nan Bei?
你觉得呢 南北
When we get the copyright...
等咱们拿到版权啊
When we get the copyright,
等咱们拿到版权
we can make a movie,
咱们做电影
an online drama,
做完电影做网剧
and then a TV play.
做完网剧做电视剧
Then the play will spread all over the world.
然后话剧全世界去
Then
然后呢
we can set the theme park and peripheral products.
就是主题乐园和周边
This is an industrial chain.
这就是一条产业链
I'll let you play
到时候让你来演
the leading actress, will you?
女一好不好
When you get your Angel Investment,
等你筹到天使轮
I will think about it.
我再考虑考虑
What about you?
那你呢
I am the director, film producer,
导演 制片
scriptwriter and the leading actor.
编剧 男一
Everybody,
各位
you should know
知道现在
why good movies
好电影为啥
are fewer and fewer.
越来越少了吧
Oops!
哎呀
I forgot to pick up the contest files.
我忘记拿比赛资料了
I left them
我把它放在
on the desk in the classroom.
教室课桌上了
Mr. Li is expecting me to go to a meeting.
主任还等着我去开会呢
Will any of you have time
你们谁有时间
to help me to get them?
帮我去拿一下吗
I'll go.
我去
You have to be at the meeting.
这会你也得开
Hao, I really want to go,
小好姐 我很想去
but,
但是
team one must be there by now,
现在一队肯定在那儿了
and that person is there,
那谁也在
I...
我
Hao, I also want to go,
小好姐 我也想去的
but that person is there
但是那谁也在
who I don't want to talk to.
不够磨牙口的
I'll go.
我去
I have time.
我闲
I have much time.
我最闲了
I am a free man.
我闲人一个
Your friend's
你这姐们
taste and thoughts are both
眼光和思想一样
dangerous.
都很危险
She has a sense of propriety.
她有分寸
Maybe...
吧
These are the notes for our team.
这是我们队的笔记
You're prying into others' privacy.
你这是在窥探隐私
It's wrong.
这样做是不对的
We were in the same varsity team.
我们是一个校队的吧
What's wrong if I concerned about team two?
关心一下二队怎么了
And I didn't see much of them.
而且我也没怎么看
Don't worry.
放心吧
Alright then.
那好吧
It's the topic from
这里面是去年
the last year's provincial final contest.
省赛决赛的题
How do you have time
你们怎么还有时间
to replay this contest?
复盘这场比赛
They are our opponents in the next competition.
我们下一场比赛的对手
Know yourself as well as the enemy.
知己知彼嘛
Do you have anything else to say?
你还有什么事吗
The cookies that day
那天的饼干
were delicious.
很好吃
Right?
对吧
I told you they were delicious!
我就说很好吃对不对
I'll make them for you if you like.
你要是喜欢我再给你做
There’s no need.
不用
I'll go to class.
我去上课了
Did you dig the potatoes?
土豆是现挖的呀
You are so slow.
这么慢
I have to wait in line.
不得排队呀
If you think I'm slow, then go by yourself next time.
嫌慢下次自己去
Do you know?
你知道吗
Your
你呀
person image in my mind is violence.
在我这儿人设就是暴力
So the person image of all the people
所以所有的人设
is a kind of
都是一种
impression in other people's minds.
别人在别人心里的印象
Am I right?
是吗
So if you think about it this way,
那照这个思路想的话
person image is the impression in other people’s minds,
人设是别人心里的印象
then setting a person image is
那立人设就是
a means of influencing others' impression.
影响别人印象的手段
But all the influence
可是所有的影响
is a kind of travesty.
都是一种歪曲呀
So setting a person image
所以立人设
is a travesty to a certain extent,
就是某种程度上的歪曲
right?
对不对
It's too farfetched.
太勉强了
If it goes back to the beginning,
那要回到最开始的话
I think
我觉得
my impression of you is violence,
我对你的印象是暴力
so is your person image violence?
你的人设就是暴力吗
Of course not.
当然不是了
Therefore,
所以说
the attribute of the person image
人设的属性
has some subjectivity.
都有一定的自主性
The person image starts with me,
人设是从我出发的
right?
对不对
But this is the opponent's point.
可这是对方的点
I disagree,
我不同意
but I think
但是我觉得
that makes sense.
还挺有道理的
What are you doing?
干嘛
I haven't been so tired lately.
最近没那么累了
In these days,
这两天来来回回
I turned down at least three people.
拒绝了至少三个人呢
Ok.
哦
I'm a lot more relaxed now.
整个人现在轻松多了
What's this?
你这是什么
Mr. Wang asked me to do this.
这个是王老师让我做的
It's the investigation
关于社会实践
about the social practice.
调查的调研
I offered to help.
是我主动要帮忙的
Because Mr. Wang said
因为王老师说
it was worth credits.
这个能算在学分里
Good for me.
赚了
You've got more credits
那你的学分
than I've
怕是比我重修的学分
ever retaken.
都多了吧
Forget it.
算了
Don't care about these.
就不跟你计较这些了
Oops!
哎呀
No! No!
不对 不对
You give me
你 你把办公室
the office key!
钥匙给我
I'm going to the office.
我去趟办公室
What's wrong?
怎么了
Gosh
哎呀
I forgot
老李给我布置的任务
the task Mr. Li gave me.
我给忘了
But this night
不是今天晚上
I have to have a dinner with Dandan.
我还得约蛋蛋吃饭
I can't go.
饭吃不了了
I have to stay up late to finish the work.
我还得熬夜赶工
I'll help you.
那我帮你改吧
After all I wrote it.
毕竟那是我写的
Really?
真的吗
Tao Hao, you are so kind.
陶好 你太好了
How can I live without you!
没有你我可怎么活呀
Don't be so dramatic.
你别这么夸张
It's okay. I'll do it.
没事 包给我了
What's wrong?
怎么了
What do you say?
你说呢
You played a trick on me!
你套路我
Yes, I am playing a trick on you.
对呀 我是在套路你
You can't cheat!
不行 你使诈
But you still believed me.
可你还是被套路了呀
Oops!
哎呀
Look!
你看
It's weak!
它没劲了
It's broken!
它断了
What kind of hand is that?
这是什么掌法你
Really, it can't move!
真的 不动了
Let's start with the definition of the person image.
先来人设的定义
What's the attribute
立人设行为
of setting a person image?
属性的判断
I think it can be discussed in terms of subjectivity
我觉得可以从自主性
and others'
和他者
empowerment.
赋予两个方面去讨论
These are the two aspects.
就这两个方面
One additional point.
补充一点
The development of the person image.
人设发展的沿路历程
Right.
没错
Mr. Li
主任
Mr. Sa
撒老师
Come here.
来 你过来一下
I need to talk to you about something.
我找你有点事
Ok.
好
You go on.
你们继续
So on social media
所以当你在社交网络
or in front of your friends,
或者是自己朋友的面前
setting a person image
给自己立了一个人设
essentially means
本质上来说
managing your image
是想要管理自己
in front of others.
在他人面前的形象
But if
可是如果要是
that is the case,
这样子的话
the person image is actually
人设其实就是
determined by others,
取决于他人
not by ourselves.
而非自己
But if you leave your fate
可如果把自己的命运
in the hands of someone else,
交给别人的话
it doesn't usually end well.
通常没有什么好下场吧
No!
不行
Mr. Li
李主任
In this way,
这样的话
it's so disrespectful to the students!
对孩子们太不尊重了
What are they talking about?
说什么呢
Listen.
再听听
This game
这场比赛
is also important
对二队来说
to team two!
也同样的重要
Have a look.
您看一下
In this month,
我们这个月
we really won a lot of games.
真的赢了很多比赛
You need to trust us!
您 您要相信我们
We can win
我们是可以拿下
this contest!
这场比赛的
What's going on?
怎么回事啊
Let me say something.
我说两句啊
Since Mr. Sa does not say,
既然撒老师不说
I'll tell you.
我跟大家说一下
For the next game against Fulin,
下场对战涪临的比赛
we decided that the team one would go first.
学校决定由一队先上
You prepare for other games.
你们准备其他的比赛
Why?
凭什么呀
Against last year's provincial runner-up,
对战去年省赛的亚军
we think the team one will be more safe.
学校认为一队稳妥一点
You team two are great, too.
你们二队也很优秀
We didn't mean anything else.
我们没有别的意思
We have signed up
我们都是通过
through formal channels.
正规渠道报名的
How can you change us freely?
怎么说换就换了
Sir, what's wrong with us?
老师 我们哪儿不合适
You are not suitable anywhere.
你们哪儿合适了
In the two years you've been in the varsity team,
你在校队这两年
our university hasn't even made it
学校连省联赛的
to the provincial finals.
决赛圈都没进过
Indeed.
真没进过
Who do you look down upon here?
你们在这儿看不起谁呢
Since it's in the name of
既然是以学校的名义
our university,
报的名
what's the problem
那我们参加有
with our participation?
什么问题吗
We just don't want to
我们也是不想
embarrass the university.
给学校丢脸
Who will embarrass the university?
谁让学校丢脸了
You embarrass the university.
你们才让学校丢脸吧
Personal attacks without ability?
没能力就人身攻击吗
Don't forget you team two...
别忘了你们二队
Team two!
一天一个二队
Without our points,
没我们二队攒积分
how can you join the contest?
你们打什么比赛啊
But we are
那我们也是
fighting for the honor of the university.
为了学校的荣誉啊
Who is not?
谁不是为了学校的荣誉
Right!
就是
Your efforts are efforts!
就你们的努力是努力
Our efforts mean nothing!
我们的努力什么都不是
Stop! Stop!
都别喊 都别喊
When we were accumulating points,
我们在攒积分的时候
what were you doing?
你们在干嘛
Disgusting!
太讨厌了
When we were accumulating points,
我们在攒积分的时候
what were you doing?
你们在干嘛
I disagree!
我不同意
From now on,
从现在起
the points for fighting against the provincial team,
校队打省队的积分
team one should accumulate by themselves.
一队自己去攒吧
I quit team two.
我退出二队
Tao Hao, wait!
陶好 你等一下
Sir, I have made up my mind.
老师 我已经决定好了
Guys,
二队的各位
if you like,
你们如果愿意的话
leave with me.
跟我走吧